ICI Lombard has introduced a very
Innovative integrated media initiative
called Game of Life this pioneering
Concept in the insurance domain combines
the excitement of gaming with the
practicality of insurance this campaign
leverages the captivating Allure of
virtual games to connect with the
digital native generation while speaking
about the uncertainties and ups and
downs of our everyday life while urging
the viewers to stay protected to tell us
more we are joined in by Shea Kapoor
head marketing corporate Communications
and CSR ICI Lombard Shea welcome to CNBC
tv18 thank you so much and it's pleasure
to be here China first of all game of
life I saw the campaign such an
interesting concept tell us more about
it how it was conceptualized what were
some of the discussions that you had
with your agency oal V I believe um and
what was the kind of brief that you gave
to them for us game of life has been a
very very uh disruptive campaign and uh
as always you know with any bfsi sector
Q4 happens to be like the most active uh
season and uh we started actually
thinking and ideating about scripts uh
way back in uh Q3 about October November
so that we're you know well in time
ready uh with the plan and uh we
actually went through some six to seven
very interesting scripts um and we
looked at different different kind of
narratives uh we were sure that we
wanted to talk about something which was
at a brand level which was at an
corporate level uh a campaign that spoke
about IC Lombard but spoke about a
different tonality and spoke about the
category uh we wanted to have something
which was a culmination of uh technology
um ideation uh creativity uh Innovation
and uh is yet very engaged
you know for the viewers especially
something that engages and appeals to
the younger audience the Millennials and
the genz and gamification so how did you
arrive upon gamifying uh you know to
communicate the objective of buying an
insurance Life's a game you really don't
know what will happen next it's so
uncertain you can't really predict
because it is unpredictable um and
insurance therefore you know as a
category we're there uh to be
um you know providing that shield and
that protection uh cover for the
consumers across whether it's you know
health insurance or whether it's motor
insurance uh to safeguard the consumers
um you know against these kind of
uncertainties as well as protecting the
assets um and so we asked ourselves okay
here is this gamification route can we
bring alive the entire concept and
bringing in the environment of a gaming
so that we make it even more cooler and
we make it more engaging and uh you know
and I think it's resonated uh very well
of course with the younger audience but
I'm happy to say that that even uh with
the older demographics it has resonated
really well so having said that I'm
tempted to ask what has it done for
ICICI Lombard uh or what can it
potentially do for the brand as compared
to what you know the traditional uh
campaign would have done so you know um
again this is far removed from anywhere
close to what traditional uh has done so
far and in fact arguably uh not just
within the insurance not even within the
bfsi I'm saying across categories um and
I'll I'd go bold enough to say within
India and arguably even across the world
this is the first time any brand has
attempted a narrative which is using a
gaming environment and uh the production
has the creative agent gencies the
director has pulled this off so
fabulously that it actually looks like
robotic characters when they're actually
humans who are uh portraying the entire
film narrative um and through the film
like I said you know we have spoken
about um you know the different aspects
of life and we've brought up the analogy
with health bar or the power bar like
you have in a game so anything that you
do which is um you know um which could
leave you one vulnerable uh to any kind
of mishap or is actually you know taking
away from your well-being actually
depletes your energy so you reaching out
for junk food even though you know that
a healthier choice exists uh is actually
not doing too you know too great for you
in the health terms in the longer run
right um and that's what we're trying to
also Advocate to the audience saying
preventive uh health care and the
overall well-being and the Continuum of
Care that we want to propose
um and as against any kind of
traditional adwar you would have
possibly taken a product you know
exemplified the features or um you know
the Contours of the product or you know
as as a lot of brands do you know engage
with even ROP in some celebrities you
know to uh pull off the narrative this
is you know extremely differentiated uh
disruptive original and very very
refreshing in fact I have been I think
the best form of uh you know uh you know
compliment that one can receive is from
the competition itself you know and from
the a lot of the marketers you know from
within the insurance and bfsi category
uh they've come forward to you know
congratulate uh us on the campaign and
have been saying that you know this has
really raised the bar uh from an
otherwise a very boring category which
is uh which is kind of you know used to
doing some boring work and not like very
disruptive work thank you so much thanks
for joining us today and thanks for
sharing these insights with us she thank
you thank you so
much